A Guide to the Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. papers FA116
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional Papers, 1958-2016; 1
  - Philippine Council for Agriculture and Resources Research and Development (PCARRD), 1984 February (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Regional Agriculture Technology Networks Report, 1986 March (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Regional Office for Central America and Panama (ROCAP) Project Implementation Document (PID), 1986 March (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Collaborative Research Networks: Desirable Characteristics, 1987 March 27 (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Tropical Agricultural Research and Training Center (CATIE), Turrialba, Costa Rica, 1987 March (Box 15, Folder 183)
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID) - Science and Technology, 1982-1988 (Box 15, Folder 184)
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID) - Agricultural Technology Management Working Papers, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 185)
  - Agricultural and Applied Economics Association (AAEA) - Brady, 1987 August (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Development Assistance and Exports: The Case of the United States, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr and Dana G. Dalrymple, 1988 July (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Project Documents and Papers, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 188)
    The Driving Force of Agricultural Technological Change in Economic Development draft, Agricultural Research Extension and Development Project, Development of Agricultural Research and Extension in the Eastern Caribbean (DAREEC), Support to Caribbean Research and Development Institute (CARDI) from sources other than Agency for International Development
  - Caribbean Research and Development Institute (CARDI), 1991 (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - External Assistance in Agricultural Extension: The US Agency for International Development Experience (USAID), Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) Global Consultation on Extension, 1989 November (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Agricultural Technology Management, International Service for National Agricultural Research (ISNAR) Workshop, Rutgers University, 1988 May (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Reverse Technology: A Key to the Successful Future of World and American Agriculture, 1990 February (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Asian Vegetable Research and Development Center - Vegetables: Research and Development in the 1990s, A Strategic Plan, 1991 October (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Caribbean Research and Development Institute (CARDI) Strategic Plan, 1994-2004 (Box 16, Folder 194)
  - Tropical Agricultural Research and Training Center (CATIE) - The Early History of the Turrialba Center, 1984 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 195)
  - A Global Partnership: Address by the US Ambassador to Nigeria at the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Eugene Chivaroli Speech, Cummings' Edits, 1993 February (Box 16, Folder 196)
  - Reverse Technology Flow as a Key to the Future World and US Agriculture, 1991 October (Box 16, Folder 197)
  - The Story of Student Government in the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 198)
    Book, p. 227 Ralph Cummings, Jr.
  - International Service for National Agricultural Research (ISNAR) - Methods for Diagnosing Research System Constraints and Assessing the Impact of Agricultural Research: Volume I: Diagnosing Agricultural Research System Complaints, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 199)
  - From Parastatals to Private Trade (2 copies), 2008 (Box 16, Folder 200-201)
    Books
  - Report of the Global Consultation on Agricultural Extension, Food and Agricultural Organization, Rome, 1989 December 4-8 (Box 16, Folder 202)
    Bound material
  - Grand Opening of Walt Disney World's Epcot Center - Realia, 1982 October; 2017:025:029 (Box 21)
    Separated Materials
    Special format items have been separated from the above listed file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number. All inquiries to view memorabilia require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Items are available at the discretion of RAC.
  - International Leadership Seminar - Walt Disney World Epcot Center - Realia, 1983; 2017:025:030 (Box 21)
  - US Department of Agriculture Honor Award Recipient - Realia, 1998; 2017:025:031 (Box 21)
  - US Department of Agriculture Honor Award Recipient - Realia, 2003; 2017:025:032 (Box 21)
  - Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. - Assistant Director, 1966-1968; 2017:025:033 (Box 21)
  - Getting Economic Development Moving in India: Lessons Learned from Forty Years of Experience, Paper Submitted to the UK Parliamentary Inquiry into Global Food Security, 2009 March (Box 17, Folder 203)
  - The World Food Summit: Five Years Later, United States of America Position Paper, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 204)
  - Our Choice: To Succeed Jointly or Fail Separately, Manuscript and Notes, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 205-208)
  - Improving the Lot of the People Left Behind, Draft, 4 of a Proposed 7 Chapters, 1982 March 29 (Box 17, Folder 209)
  - Improving the Lot of the People Left Behind (with attached notes), 1982 March 29 (Box 17, Folder 210)
  - Promoting Food Security: Lessons Learned from Forty Years of Experience in Asia, 2012 June 28 (Box 17, Folder 211)
  - If We Can Put a Man on the Moon, Why Can't We Eliminate Poverty and Hunger for Everyone on Earth?, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 212)
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID) Publications Prepared by Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 213)
  - Agricultural Diversification Towards High Value Commodities: A Study in Food Surplus States in India with Focus on Andhra Pradesh and Punjab, International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI), New Delhi, 2007 March (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - Foodgrains Policy and Management in India: Responding to Today's Challenges and Opportunities, A. Ganesh Kumar, Ashok Gulati and Ralph Cummings, Jr, International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI), New Delhi, 2007 March (Box 18, Folder 215)
  - Withering Punjab Agriculture: Can It Regain Its Leadership?, International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI), New Delhi, 2007 March (Box 18, Folder 216)
  - Re-energizing Agricultural Sector of Andhra Pradesh: From Food Security to Income Opportunities, International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI), New Delhi, 2007 March (Box 18, Folder 217)
  - International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI) - Markets, Trade and Institutions Division (MTID) Discussion Paper No. 80, Grain Marketing Parastatals in Asia: Why Do They Have to Change Now?, Shahidur Rashid, Ralph Cummings, Jr and Ashok Gulati, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 218)
  - Every Country Can Do It: End Hunger Now!, Draft, 2013 May 31 (Box 18, Folder 219)
  - Drafts of Manuscripts and Research Materials, 1979-2009 (Box 18, Folder 220)
    Includes Putting First-Things First in Promoting Poverty Reduction, Food Security, and Employment: Identifying and Mobilizing the Development Potential of the Agricultural Sector, Every Country Can Do It: End Hunger Now, Grain Price Stabilization Experiences in Asia: What Have We Learned?, The State of Food Security in the World, Mycorrhiza, A Fungal Solution for the Farm Economy, From Plate to Plough: A Challenge for Change, and Punjab Agriculture at the Crossroad
  - Experience with Managing Foodgrains Price Volatility in Asia, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 221)
  - Frank Galtier - Advisory Service in Social Transfers (ASiST) Project Funded by the European Commission, 2016 (Box 18, Folder 222, Box 19, Folder 223-225)
- Cummings Family Files, 1941-2002; 2
  - Correspondence and Clippings, 1989; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Correspondence regarding the awarding of the 1995 Watauga Medal from North Carolina State Board of Trustees to Cummings' father, Ralph Waldo Cummings, and clippings related to the obituary of Cummings' mother, Mary Parrish Cummings.
  - 1988 Presidential End Hunger Awards (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Awarded to Cummings' father, Ralph Waldo Cummings, Sr.
  - Clippings and Notes, 1968-2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Clippings related to Cummings family members and the International Crop Research Insitute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT), Hyderabad, India
  - About the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT), 1973 November (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Pamphlet
  - Ralph W. Cummings, Sr. portrait, undated; 2017:025:001 (Box 20, Folder 226)
  - Cummings Family Awards and Memorials, 1966-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Remarks given by Ralph Cummings, Jr. at the dedication of Mary Cummings Park on the ICRISAT Campus, memorialization of his father, Ralph W. Cummings, clippings, and information/printed photos relating to the Watauga Award given to Ralph Cummings, Sr. from North Carolina State University.
  - Correspondence - V. Balasubramanian to Ralph Cummings, Jr, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Cummings in India photographs, undated; 2017:025:002 (Box 20, Folder 227)
    Photographs of Ralph W. Cummings, Sr. and Mary Cummings in India from V. Balasubramanian's personal collection
  - Dr. and Mrs. Ralph W. Cummings, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dedication of Ralph W. Cummings Laboratory, 1966 October 25; 2017:025:003 (Box 20, Folder 228)
  - North Carolina State University Alumni Magazine, 1991 September (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Feature on Ralph Waldo Cummings, Sr.
  - Correspondence - E. Gordon Gee to Ralph Cummings, Jr., 1993 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - RW Cummings work with the International Corps Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) photographs, 1972-1996; 2017:025:004 (Box 20, Folder 229)
    Photographs documenting Ralph W. Cummings' work with the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT), including the governing boards' meetings, and dedication of Mary Cummings Park
  - Report of the Agricultural Research Review Team, New Delhi, 1964 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - North Carolina State University Alumni Association Awards Luncheon, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Ralph W. Cummings, Sr. presented Meritorious Service Award
  - Report of the Second Joint Indo-American Team on Agricultural Research and Extension, Indian Council of Agricultural Research, New Delhi, 1960 July (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Asian Agri-History, Volume 5, Number 4, 2001 October-December (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Contains obituary for Ralph Cummings, Sr.
  - Address Presented to Dr. Ralph W. Cummings and Mrs. Mary Cummings, 1966 November 23; 2017:025:005 (Box 22)
    Special format items have been separated from the above listed file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - The International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) Tripod CD (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - Degree from Ohio State University (Box 2, Item 2017:025:006)
  - Indian Agricultural Research Institute (IARI) photographs, 1966-1987; 2017:025:007 (Box 20, Folder 230)
  - Mary Cummings Park Dedication Ceremony, 1990 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dedication Ceremony for Mary Cummings Park photographs, 1990 September 18; 2017:025:008 (Box 20, Folder 231)
  - Graduation Exercises, North Carolina State University, Honorary Doctorate, 1968 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Honorary degree awarded to Ralph W. Cummings, Sr.
  - Alumni News - North Carolina State College, 1941 December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Blueprint For a Rural University in India, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Report of the Joint Indo American Team on Agricultural Research and Education, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ralph Waldo Cummings Biography, Draft, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Biography of Ralph W. Cummings, Sr.
  - Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger: Selected Papers of J. George Harrar, President, The Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Bound volume
  - Invitation to 50th Wedding Anniversary Party of Ralph and Mary Cummings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - The Establishment of Agricultural Universities in India: A Case Study of the Role of US Agency for International Development (USAID)-US University Technical Assistance, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International - Paul Harris Fellow -Pin, 2017:025:011 (Box 21)
    3 medals and 1 small pin
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International - Paul Harris Fellow - Metal, 2017:025:012 (Box 21)
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International - Paul Harris Fellow -Metal, 2017:025:013 (Box 21)
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International - Paul Harris Fellow - Metal, 2017:025:014 (Box 21)
  - Honorary Doctor of Education Degree from Ohio State University, 1992 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Honorary Doctor of Science Degree from North Carolina State University - Raleigh, 1968 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Father, We Thank You, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    Children's book with inscription related to the obituary of Ralph Cummings, Sr. by Park and Thacher